lifeout.com 2019-03-21

# LifeOUT.com · Privacy Policy

### Last updated 2018-05-20.

At LifeOUT Systems, LLC we believe that your privacy is paramount, and therefore we have created this policy in recognition of your rights to keep personal information personal. This statement details our information gathering and dissemination practices for LifeOUT.com. This privacy notice has been created to inform you about:

  * The Terms that we use in this Notice
  * Categories of data
  * When we collect data from you
  * Special Category Data
  * Cookies and other data stored on your browser
  * Children's Privacy
  * Why we need the data that you provide
  * Advertising
  * What we do with your data
  * An overview of the security measures that we take to look after your data
  * How we process your photos and images
  * Automated Decisions
  * Access to your data by LifeOUT Systems' staff
  * Information sharing and third parties
  * Your rights with respect to your personal data
  * Our Company and Data Protection Officer Details
  * LifeOUT Systems' Right to Amend this notice

LifeOUT Systems, LLC takes privacy very seriously, especially given the sensitive nature of some of the data that we handle. This notice sets out how we treat your personal data and how we expect you to treat any personal data with which you come into contact on LifeOUT.com. Please read it carefully before using the site as it concerns use of your personal information.

LifeOUT.com staff will never ask you for your password. Please help us to protect your privacy by keeping your password safe and not sharing it with anyone.

### Terms that we use in this Notice

"We", "us", "our" refers to LifeOUT Systems, LLC. We are the controller and are responsible for your personal data.

"You", "your" refers to the member or user.

"LifeOUT" refers to the website [www.lifeout.com](https://www.lifeout.com/), which is wholly owned and operated by us.

EU refers to the European Union.

EEA refers to the European Economic Area.

You should be aware that these terms apply equally irrespective of whether the products or services are accessed via a desktop browser, mobile browser, mobile phone, tablet device, or any other digital device.

### What data do you collect about me?

#### Categories of data

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

  * Identity data includes first name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender.
  * Contact data includes billing address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * Financial data includes bank account and payment card details.
  * Transaction data includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.
  * Technical data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access our services.
  * Profile data includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
  * Usage data includes information about how you use our websites app, products and services.
  * Marketing and communications data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and third parties and your communication preferences.

Some of the data that we collect for your LifeOUT profile and from surveys and face to face interviews is very personal. You can see more about this in the section called "Special Category Data".

For a full list and explanation see [Your Data and How we Process It](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicy.php?mode=your-data#page-top).

#### When we collect data from you

We collect data from you:

  * Directly, when you enter information (active data)
  * Indirectly when you take some action on the site (passive data)
  * When you contact our Customer Services Team

We may also have personal data about you, if you:

  * Have participated in surveys or agreed to be interviewed to help us with our research
  * Have modelled for us
  * Have placed an advertisement with us
  * Are a LifeOUT Systems, LLC supplier
  * Are an employee or former employee of LifeOUT Systems, LLC

We don't use publicly-available information about you, however we do receive access to some personal information from our payment provider when you purchase a premium membership.

For a full list and explanation see the following:

#### Special Category Data

When you create a profile on LifeOUT, we ask you to disclose some special category personal data about your sexual orientation and your sex life so that you, and other members, can find people with similar interests.

You also have the option to disclose your ethnicity and your attitude to safer sex, however these are optional fields. If you choose not to disclose your ethnicity or your attitude to safer sex, your profile will not display them, and you won’t appear in searches where specific attributes of these categories of data are specified.

The special category data on your profile is visible to all other members including those who have joined but not yet created a profile.

You can also request a link (URL) that gives access to your profile from the web. If you choose this option, you should be aware that your personal data, including special category data, will be visible to anyone on the Internet who has, or guesses, your URL.

#### Cookies and Information Stored on Browsers

We also set cookies and store information on your browser. This allows us to take you back to where you were on LifeOUT and to remember your password, if you use this option. These cookies and how we use browser storage are described in the section [Cookies and Browser Storage](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicy.php?mode=cookies).

Some third-party sites may set cookies if you click on their advertisements. LifeOUT Systems, LLC doesn't control these cookies, but you can use browser settings to do this yourself. You can find links to the browser instructions in the section [Changing Your Cookie Options](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicy.php?mode=cookies).

#### Children's Privacy

We restrict the use of our service to individuals aged 18 years and above. We do not knowingly collect, maintain or use personal information from children under the age of 18 years.

Should we have a valid reason to believe that you are too young to join the site, we shall immediately suspend your account and contact you to request further proof of age. Until you provide proof to satisfy us that you are indeed aged 18 years or over, you will not be able to use the non-public areas of the site. If you do not provide proof of age within the required timeframe, your data will be permanently deleted apart from the minimum required for safeguarding purposes.

### Why do you need my data?

#### Why we need the data that you provide

On LifeOUT, we use the data that we collect to fulfil the contract that we have with you to provide our services.

  * Providing you with a profile
  * Finding and interacting with other members
  * Uploading and managing photos
  * Providing news and views

You can see a full list of the data collected on LifeOUT and what it is used for in the section [Your Data and How we Process It](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicy.php?mode=your-data).

We don't combine your payment information with your LifeOUT profile, only the fact that you have paid.

If you are a supplier, photographer, or have modelled for us, we may have your contact details, contracts, and other information connected with the work that you have done for us. We keep this data if we are required to for accounting, legal and contractual reasons.

#### Advertising

Part of our revenue is derived from advertising on our sites and apps, including sponsored member messages and news articles. This enables us to provide some of the services on our site free of charge. All advertising is booked through our own advertising department to ensure that it is relevant to our members. When you click on a link within an advert on our site, you may be taken to the advertiser's site. This privacy notice will no longer apply while you are on their site, and you should ensure that you read their privacy notice carefully.

### What happens to my data?

#### What we do with your data

Your data is uploaded onto servers, all of which are in data centers in the United States of America.

We process your IP address and your date of birth to determine your eligibility to join LifeOUT. Your date of birth is also used to calculate your age for your profile. Your IP address may be used to resolve queries.

We process your chosen member name and password to provide secure access to LifeOUT and your profile data.

We process your profile data to provide you with a page that enables your fellow-members to get to know you.

We pass your payment data directly to our payment provider when you purchase or renew a premium membership. Our payment provider supplies us with access to transaction details which, in exceptional circumstances, we may need to access to help confirm your identity should you contact us with a problem.

We process your contact details to reply to you.

#### An overview of the security measures that we take to look after your data

We employ several security measures to help limit the loss, damage, misuse and defacement of information that we control. Information that is gathered by us is stored on our secure servers in the United States of America, which are protected by physical and electronic security.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

#### How we process your photos and images

Photos that you upload to LifeOUT must meet the standards that we set out in our [User Agreement](https://www.lifeout.com/useragreement.php). The photographs are stored in the United States of America and are not permanently stored elsewhere. Any images that do not comply with our User Agreement are deleted. You can decide whether to make an image available for other members to view, to place the image in your private gallery or to delete it if you want to, however it may be moved to your private gallery automatically depending on the classification.

#### Automated Decisions

We use proprietary algorithms to detect spammers and abuse. If you think that you have been refused an account in error, you have a right to request that we assess your eligibility manually. You can request this by contacting our [Support Team](https://www.lifeout.com/support.php). Once assessed manually, LifeOUT's decision is final. We retain a small amount of data from applications that are refused to enable these algorithms to protect our members.

### Who else can see my data?

#### Access to your data by LifeOUT's Staff

Access to your data by LifeOUT's staff is restricted to only those required to provide and maintain our services to you. Should we need to access your data for any reason, we will inform you unless prevented from doing so by law. Please note, however, that some members of staff are also genuine members of our sites and are acting in a purely personal capacity in this regard.

#### Information sharing and Third Parties

To provide the best service to you we may have to share your personal data with the third parties set out in this privacy notice.

Our payment-processing partner uses industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to ensure that information between yourself and their servers is encrypted; the purchasing system is secure and any information passed between your computer or mobile device and the payment-processing computer cannot be read by anyone that happens to intercept it.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

### What are my rights?

#### Your rights with respect to your personal data

You have the following rights:

  * To be told [how we process your data](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicydata.php#page-top) and whether we are using any sort of [automated decision making](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicydata.php#automated-decisions)
  * You can request access to and rectification or erasure of your personal data in the section [Your options if you want us to provide access to, rectify or erase your personal data](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicy.php?mode=data-deletion)
  * You can [ask us to restrict processing](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicy.php?mode=restrict-processing) of your personal data
  * You can [withdraw consent](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicy.php?mode=withdraw-consent) for us to process your personal data; this won’t affect any lawful processing done before you withdrew consent
  * To know whether the data is required [in relation to a contract](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicy.php?mode=contract-with-us) and any consequences of not providing it.
  * To [object to the processing of your personal data](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicy.php?mode=options-to-object).
  * To [request a transfer of your personal data](https://www.lifeout.com/privacypolicy.php?mode=options-to-transfer).

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact our [Support Team](https://www.lifeout.com/support.php).

### How do I contact you about my data?

#### Our company and Data Protection Officer details

LifeOUT Systems, LLC  
PO Box 341003  
Dayton, OH 45434-1003

You can contact LifeOUT's Data Protection Officer by emailing support@lifeoutsystems.com

#### LifeOUT's Right to Amend this notice

We may at any time revise the terms of this notice by posting changes on our sites, and/or, where appropriate, notifying to you by email or by notifying you of a change when you next start the Apps or log onto one of LifeOUT's sites. The new terms may be displayed on-screen and you may be required to read and accept them to continue your use of that site. The continued use our services after changes are posted constitutes your acceptance of the modified terms. If you choose not to accept the modified terms and you are a fee-paying member, we will upon request return a fair proportion (related to the time left unexpired on your membership) of the membership fee.

#### Applicable laws

The terms of this notice are governed and construed in accordance with the laws of Ohio and the United States of America. If any of the terms is held to be unlawful, void or for any reason unenforceable, then that provision will be deemed severable and will not affect the validity and enforceability of the remaining terms. You agree to submit to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of the United States of America courts.
